mysupermarket.co.uk 2018-12-17

# Privacy Policy – How can we help you

Hello! Welcome to mySupermarket’s Privacy Policy! Please note that any words which are capitalised have the same meaning as in the [Terms & Conditions](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/mysupermarket-terms-of-use/)  for use of the Sites and the Service.

We are mySupermarket Limited, Company No 5920495 registered in England with our registered office at Lower Ground Floor, 1 Great Cumberland Place, London, W1H 7AP, England.  In this privacy policy, you’ll see us refer to ourselves as “mySupermarket”, “we” or “us” or “our”. 

Throughout this privacy policy, we refer to “GDPR” – which is shorthand for an EU-wide General Data Protection Regulation.  The GDPR deals with:

  * your right to privacy;
  * your rights to information about, and relating to, you – and how it is used; and
  * your rights to data security.

The GDPR approaches these from two directions. On the one hand, it sets out various rules for companies like us regarding their collection and processing of information relating to an individual. (“Processing” here means “use” or “deal with”, and refers pretty much to anything one can do with information about individuals – from storing it in a database, to combining it with other information and building profiles. ) On the other hand, GDPR sets out rights for individuals.  These rights are designed, again, to give you more control over your privacy and information relating to you.

We’ve put together a brief overview of your rights under the law as they are most likely to apply to your use of mySupermarket.  In addition, we recommend that you check out the ICO website, which has more information on your rights.

The GDPR (see, there it is) sets out a limited number of different reasons which allow us, as a company, to collect and process information relating to you.  Each reason is known as a “legal basis to process” and we need one of these for each bit of processing we do. Below, you will find a list of the activities we engage in which involved information relating to you – and we set out the legal basis (you know … that “allowable reason”!) for each activity.

You will note that several of the activities listed are commercial. In other words, we earn money from them.  mySupermarket does not charge individual consumers to use mySupermarket so advertising, data analysis and that sort of thing allow us to keep the lights on and the site up and running.

[See here to learn more about each activity below for any of the 3 GDPR reasons – and why we have classed it as we have.](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/additional-detail-on-mysupermarket-activities/)

[See here to learn more about the legal bases (that is, those GDPR reasons) themselves, and your rights under each](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/legal-reasons-why-we-are-allowed-to-deal-with-information-relating-to-you/)[.](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/legal-reasons-why-we-are-allowed-to-deal-with-information-relating-to-you/)

Reason number 1: We have a contract with you

Because we have a contract with you, we use information relating to you (such as your email address or post code) for contract and account management.  (In other words, we provide you with the website’s services).

Reason number 2: We have your specific and informed consent

We have collected (or not) your specific, informed consent for:

  * Sharing of User activity data with third parties for use in their own targeted marketing, audience building, market research, analysis or other activities; and
  * Targeted advertising on mySupermarket, where the targeting is not conducted by ourselves.

Obviously, if don’t have your consent, we won’t do that stuff (but it helps us pay the bills if you do consent!) Also, if you have given us your consent for each of these, you have a right to withdraw your consent at any time.

Reason number 3: It is in our legitimate interests (we need to market to you to pay the bills!) to do the following:

  * Direct email marketing. (We always allow you to opt-out of this in each email.)
  * Targeted (or “behavioural”) advertising campaigns and promotional activities on the mySupermarket website, where the campaign or activity is conducted by ourselves. _(You can learn more about behavioural advertising at[Your Online Choices)](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/)_

 Other stuff:

We use data for other stuff too – but it’s not data about or related to you and so it’s not regulated by the GDPR. Although the law doesn’t say we need to tell you about this, we believe in being completely transparent with you – so we’re going to tell you anyway!

We carry out:

  * Analyses of aggregated and anonymised User usage and activity data for purposes of site maintenance, development and evaluation. We have no idea from this about anything related to you. (“Aggregated and anonymised” information means information we collect about a group or category of products, services or users, from which individual user identities have been removed and from which it is not possible to work out individual customer identities.)
  * Market and business research based on aggregated and anonymised User data, for example from seeing how popular one product is in comparison with another. Again, we have no idea from this about anything related to you.
  * Advertising campaigns on mySupermarket where the ads shown are based on the page content (e.g. the products shown on that page) or other factors not based on a User’s personal data. Again, this is shown to you based on information which is nothing to do with you or your preferences or anything else!
  * Affiliate marketing in which we receive commissions from Supermarkets for “referring” customers. We participate in various referral programs under which we receive commissions from Supermarkets for “referring” customers who then complete purchases from their sites.  Some of these are run directly by the Supermarkets. In other cases, a Supermarket may choose to use a third party affiliate network to run their referral programme on their behalf.   When a shopper completes a purchase on the mySupermarket Site which may be eligible for a referral commission, a tracking code provided by the affiliate network or the Supermarket may be placed on the user device.  The code allows the affiliate network to identify shoppers referred by mySupermarket.  Apart from a partial IP address, no information relating to you or transaction data is provided to or collected by the affiliate network from mySupermarket. ****

We collect information relating to you both directly and indirectly.  This data includes:

  * Information relating to you (which we call “personal data”)
  * Activity information data (which we call “activity data”) – which is information about what you do on the Site.

Some items are universal; we collect this information from every person that uses our site, whether they register or not.  Other information is collected only when you register for the site.  And some information is collected on an as-needed basis. That is, if you want to use a feature of the site, we will ask for particular this information in order to provide that feature to you.

A breakdown of what we collect and when we collect it is below.

**What we ask for**|  **Why we ask for it**  
---|---  
IP address/ mobile identifier | When you want to…use the mySupermarket website. This is used for technical purposes as well as for fraud and abuse prevention. (We collect this from all users).  
Postcode | When you want to…browse supermarkets on mySupermarket. The postcode allows us to identify stores in your geographic area. (We collect this from all users).  
Name| When you want to…register for the site.  
Email address and password| When you want to…register for the site. You can learn more about how we use email addresses in “How we use data” section, below.   
Physical address| ● When you want to…register for a Supermarket website via the Site.  
● When you want to…book a Supermarket delivery slot via the Site.   
Login details for a Supermarket| ● When you want to…import your Favourites from that Supermarket and keep them updated.  
● When you want to…send a basket through to a Supermarket.  
● When you want to…book a Supermarket delivery slot via mySupermarket.  
PayPal account details| When you want to…participate in our Cashback program.  
Date of birth, age range or gender| When you want to…register for mySupermarket using Facebook and have permitted Facebook to include this information as part of your public profile.  
Geolocation| When you want to…use our app. This is optional and will apply only if you allow access in your smartphone location services.   
  
On the My Account page you can view or amend your: postcode, name, email address, password, Supermarket login details, PayPal account details and date of birth.  You may also delete your physical address, Supermarket login details, PayPal account details or date of birth (also from the My Account page page).

_Activity data_

We collect the following information about your activity on the Site:

  * Information on what you buy and how you use mySupermarket, such as: 
    * information on baskets you have sent on to a Supermarket;
    * your favourites;
    * your sorting preferences;
    * your product swaps, basket ‘splits’ and store ‘switches’;
    * other details about your shops and how you have used the Sites;
  * Information about your use of various mySupermarket services;
  * Information about any cashback amounts you have received from our cashback programme;
  * Your communications with us;
  * Other Information related to your use of the Services;
  * Other information related to your activity, such as which website referred you to us.

_Sensitive Personal Data_

Some information about you is more sensitive than other information about you. “Sensitive” information is defined by the GDPR and includes details such as information related to your health, sexual orientation, religion, race or ethnic origin. As you might imagine, we do not ask you to provide any such sensitive information and we do not need it in order to provide services. However, please be aware that we may be able to infer sensitive personal data about you from the products you select and your other activity on the site – but we do not knowingly make such inferences and we do not keep any records of any of this or use it in any way.

_Surveys_

In addition to the data listed above, from time to time we run surveys of our users so we can learn more about consumer behaviour in general and our users in particular.  These surveys usually include additional demographic data, such as income range or profession. You might be invited to participate. Such participation is always voluntary and it will always be clear from the invitation that this is a voluntary survey, and not information that is required to be provided in order to use our Website. If you do participate, any data provided will be used as part of out for market and business research and analysis only our market research studies only. While we use anonymised and aggregated data as part of our commercial activities, individual data is never sold.  ****

Now that you know what information we collect, the next question is what are we _doing_ with all that information? A list of each item of information – and how we use it – appears below.  As a reminder, some of our uses are commercial.  We’ve put a **£** by each relevant one so you can identify it easily.

Information we have| What we use it for  
---|---  
IP address/ mobile identifier | ● For communicating with you (technical purposes)  
● For fraud and abuse prevention  
● **(£)** For affiliate marketing   
Postcode| ● For identifying which Supermarkets are located in and/or deliver to your area and what products are available at each, as products may vary by locality  
● To produce analyses of anonymised and aggregated Site usage and activity data for purposes of site maintenance, development and evaluation (all based on just the first part of the postcode)  
● **(£)** For market and business research and analysis based on anonymised and aggregated User data (so based on just the first part of the postcode)   
● **(£)** For targeted (“behavioural”) advertising campaigns and audience building   
● **(£)** For sharing of User activity data with third parties for use in their own targeted marketing, audience building, market research, analysis or other activities (first part of the postcode only)  
  
Name| ● To communicate with you (it’s much friendlier than “hey you!”)  
● For fraud and abuse prevention  
● To register for a Supermarket website through mySupermarket  
Email address | ● For service emails, that is, emails that are directly related to and part of your use of the Services. For example:  
o sending a confirmation after you register for the Site or after you send a basket through to a Supermarket  
o sending you Price Alerts, brand store updates or other information or updates you have signed up for or asked for  
o contacting you regarding ratings or reviews you have submitted via our Site  
● **(£)** direct email marketing 

You can opt out of direct email marketing at any time from the My Account page or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email. You cannot opt out of service emails, where you are receiving emails because you signed up for a service but you may always cancel your participation in that service.   
  
Physical address| ● To register for a Supermarket website through mySupermarket  
● To book a delivery slot with a Supermarket through mySupermarket   
Login details for a Supermarket| ● To import your Favourites from a Supermarket and keep them updated.  
● To send a basket through to a Supermarket.  
● To book a Supermarket delivery slot via mySupermarket.  
● To confirm completion of orders placed on a Supermarket website via mySupermarket, including collecting information about your purchase from the third-party Supermarket website. This may be to confirm your eligibility for Cashback or for other verification reasons.  
PayPal account details| ● To pay you cashback as part of our cashback programme  
Date of birth, age range or gender| ● For analyses of anonymised and aggregated usage and activity data for purposes of site maintenance, development and evaluation   
● **(£)** For market and business research and analysis based on anonymised and aggregated data   
● **(£)** For targeted (“behavioural”) advertising campaigns and audience building   
Geolocation| ● To identify which Supermarkets are in your immediate vicinity   
● **(£)** For market and business research and analysis based on anonymised and aggregated data (so based on your general – not your specific – area)   
● **(£)** For targeted (“behavioural”) advertising campaigns and audience building   
Activity Data| ● To customise and improve your mySupermarket experience  
● For analyses of aggregated and anonymized User usage and activity data for purposes of site maintenance, development and evaluation  
● For fraud and abuse prevention   
● **(£)** For advertising campaigns based on factors other than information about you  
● **(£)** For market and business research and analysis based on anonymised and aggregated data   
● **(£)** For targeted (“behavioural”) advertising campaigns and audience building   
● **(£)** For sharing of User activity data with third parties for use in their own targeted marketing, audience building, market research, analysis or other activities  
  
To learn about the legal reasons that allow us to use this information, please see “ **Why we are allowed to use information relating to you** ”, above.

For registered users, we keep information relating to you for 3 years after your last visit to the Site (or you use the app) after which we will close your account and delete that information.  We will send you a notice before we do that.  If you want us to keep that information, simply log into your account.

We keep activity data for all accounts and Users, whether registered or not, including accounts which have been closed. However, once the personal bits have been deleted that activity data is completely anonymous and we have on way of linking back to any individual. 

We take the security of information relating to you very seriously. To learn about how we protect this , please see our [Security Policy.](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/10-security-policy/)

We may send your information internationally for the purposes above in this policy – including to countries outside the European Economic Area.  Where we do so, we always ensure that any transfers are done in accordance with the GDPR and that we have vetted and checked out that anyone processing it for us outside of the European Economic Area is subject to standards of protection for that information which are at least as good as the protections in the GDPR – and that you have the same rights in respect of that information.  This will usually be to a country which the European Commission has declared which has laws with as much protection for you as the GDPR give you.

In certain cases, we may share personal information relating to you with third parties. All recipients of that information must treat it in accordance with the GDPR, any other applicable laws and this Privacy Policy.

An overview of our data sharing activities is as follows:

**Reasons why we share information relating to you**|  **This means…**  
---|---  
Operating purposes| We share information with third parties who provide us with services that help us to operate our Sites or our business. In this case, information is provided to the extent necessary for the third party to provide their services and any information provided to them may only be used as we instruct. They aren’t allowed to go and use it for their own purposes!   
Corporate and statutory purposes| We share information when we are required to by law. We may also transfer our databases (which might include information relating to you) if we sell our business or part of it.   
Third parties with whom we have a commercial relationship|  **(£)** We may share information with third parties with whom we have a commercial relationship. In certain cases, we will need to obtain your consent before providing information to these third parties.  
If you have given consent, you can change your mind and change your consent choices at any time from the My Account page. Look for the “Privacy Settings” button on the bottom right corner of the screen.   
  
A list of the companies with whom we currently share data as part of a commercial relationship appear below.

**Company**|  **What we do with them**|  **Information shared**  
---|---|---  
Awin| We participate in affiliate marketing programs set up by Supermarkets and run on their behalf by Awin

| Partial IP address  
Carambola| Carambola serves advertising campaigns on mySupermarket. The ads are in the form of sponsored content, such as trivia, tips or quizzes. The specific advertisements shown may be general or based on page content (e.g. the category or products on that page). 

| Country-level geolocation  
Criteo| Criteo serves advertising campaigns on mySupermarket. These campaigns are generally to promote sponsored products. The specific advertisements shown may be general or may be based on the page content (e.g. the category or products on that page). 

Criteo collects some activity data so as to understand how users in general shop online so they can be more effective in ad placement. The data collected from mySupermarket is not used to create user profiles, is not combined with data from any other sources and is not shared with any other third parties. It is used for purposes of operating the mySupermarket campaigns only. 

| Activity data   
Teads| Teads provides a technology platform that is used to buy, sell, and deliver online interactive and personalized video and image advertising on mySupermarket, as well as for the collection, processing and use of data used as a basis for targeted and content-based media campaigns. The platform can be used both by Teads and by its third party partners to deliver advertising on mySupermarket. 

| Activity data  
IP address  
Internet network data  
Geolocation data (Country and city)  
Browser type  
Device information  
Other non-personal information  
  
Tradedoubler| We participate in affiliate marketing programs set up by Supermarkets and run on their behalf by Tradedoubler

|   
Online advertisers/ Data companies| mySupermarket, our media partners and our advertising networks work with a number of companies offering technology platforms that are used to buy, sell, and deliver online advertising, as well as for the collection, processing and use of data used as a basis for targeted and content-based media campaigns. These platforms may themselves buy, sell, or deliver ads, or they may solely provide technology or services (e.g. data collection, market research and audience building) that their clients use for those purposes. mySupermarket also works with data companies that collect and process data for research purposes. 

These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other third-party websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. The information collected can also be used to infer things about you, such as your demographics (age, gender etc.) 

We will need to obtain your consent before providing information to these third parties or allowing them to collect data from this site. You can see a list of third party vendors and manage your consent choices at any time. Simply go to the My Account page and look for the “Privacy Settings” button on the bottom right corner of the screen. 

| Information collected will vary from partner to partner. The key categories of data collected are:   
Activity data  
IP address  
Internet network data  
Geolocation data  
Browser type  
Device information  
Other non-personal information  

We, our service providers and other partners use cookies and other technology both to provide Services and to collect personal data and activity data.  You can find more information on the cookies used by mySupermarket, our service providers and other partners as well as how to manage your cookie choices in our [Cookie Policy.](http://help.mysupermarket.co.uk/index.php/knowledgebase/mysupermarket-cookie-policy/) 

If you have any additional questions about our privacy policy or how we use your data, please feel free to be in touch with our Data Protection Officer at DPO@mySupermarket.com. 

If you feel that we have not handled information relating to you properly, or if you have contacted us about how we use that information and are unhappy with our response, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

By phone:  0303 123 1113.  
Online:  [https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ ](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)

Updated 24 May 2018
